# AKASH GIRI

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## 

Technologies, Tools and Database: MERN(MongoDB, Express, React and Node), React Native, nextjs, Bootstrap, GraphQL, Git, JIRA, postgreSQL, etc.

#### EDUCATION

Ontario College Graduate Certificate On Computer Software and Database Development

## **Loyalist College**

Jan 2023 - Aug 2024

Courses: Emerging Dev Technologies, Full Stack Software Development, Database Management, Web Security

#### **Bachelor's in Computer Engineering**

## **Kathmandu University**

Sep 2016 - Nov 2020

Courses: Data Structure and Algorithms(DSA), System Analysis and Design, Human Computer Interaction(HCI), Software Engineering, Database Management System, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Graphics

## LANGUAGES

English		
Nepali	_	
Hindi		

#### PROFILE

Software Developer with almost 3 years of professional experience in the Front-end and Mobile Application Development. Exploring and growing in the software development field every month by 5% through practice, research and interest to learn about the market requirement according to the present context. My expertise extends to developing elegant and responsive UIs, implementing complex functionalities, and optimizing performance to meet and exceed client expectations. Committed to delivering high-quality solutions that align with industry best practices

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Freelancing Mobile Application Developer**

Vinhood

June 2023 - Present

- Development of Vinhood Mobile Application, which is a wine recommendation platform that suggests wine for the customer's based on their taste.
- Technologies Used: React Native, Storybook, Jira, Git, Redux, etc.

## **Software Developer**

Touchware IT Service Pvt. Ltd. (Kotuko)

June 2022 - Dec 2022

- Implemented Storybook to streamline the development and testing of UI components, reducing development time by 25% as measured by code review feedback and post-release bug reports.
- Technologies Used: React Native, Redux, Storybook, Rest API's, Slack, Jira, Git, etc.

## **React / React Native Developer**

Softhover

Dec 2020 - May 2022

- Created a ReactJS-based admin interface for the website and transitioned an
  existing React web app of TripLocator, which is an online travel company which
  specializes in providing travel services, to React Native, meeting project
  requirements and enhancing the platform's administrative capabilities.
- Technologies Used: React, React Native, API's, Git, Redux, Context API, nextjs, GraphQL, npm/ yarn,node, etc.

#### **Projects**

## 1. Sahooji

Sahooji is a platform created with the motive of providing services to the
customers with ease which includes plumbing, hair salons, electricity issues and
so on. This is the mobile application created using React Native, Typescript,
GraphQL, postgreSQL, etc.

#### 2. KU Canteen Management System

 This is a semester project of university which was created to make it easy for every novice user to use this Canteen System of our university following the principles of Human Computer Interaction. Python programming language was used to develop this application.

\_\_\_\_\_\_

#### **Participations/Certifications**

- Designer of IT Express Magazine
- 10 Days Conference of Second Nepal Winter School in Artificial Intelligence(AI)
  - -> Selected among 10,000 applicants to participate for this conference where the top instructor and the participants from different countries have been involved
- · React Certification from HackerRank
- Certified Learning AWS(Amazon Web Services) for Developers